<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clinical Trial on Benjamen's Homepage</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/categories/clinical-trial/</link><description>Recent content in Clinical Trial on Benjamen's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 13:06:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/categories/clinical-trial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled study of Vinpocetine for increasing IQ</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/projects/masters/clinical-trials-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 13:06:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/projects/masters/clinical-trials-2/</guid><description>In this project I propose a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled study of Vinpocetine for increasing IQ points. I will measure the change from baseline of IQ after 28 days of receiving 10mg of Vinpocetine daily. Block randomisation with multiple block sizes will be utilised. The clinically relevant difference between the placebo and test groups will be 10 IQ points, in a population of healthy individuals aged 18-64 years. The primary analysis will be ANCOVA, and I estimate a required total sample size of 88 individuals, and 65 days to complete the study.</description></item><item><title>The Ethical Issues of Placebo Control Trials</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/projects/masters/clinical-trials-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 13:06:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/projects/masters/clinical-trials-1/</guid><description>In this project I was tasked with reviewing the WMA declaration of Helsinki: Ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects, the ICH E10: Choice of control group and related issues in clinical trials harmonised tripartite guideline, and other sources to identify the ethical issues in placebo control trials and the methodological issues in active control trials, and explain how each might be overcome by design modifications.
Length: 3 pages Report: The Ethical Issues of Placebo Control Trials This project formed part of my Masters in Statistics.</description></item></channel></rss>