<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Epidemics on Benjamen's Homepage</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/tags/epidemics/</link><description>Recent content in Epidemics on Benjamen's Homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:06:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/tags/epidemics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Introduction to Epidemic Modelling</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/an-introduction-to-epidemic-modelling/an-introduction-to-epidemic-modelling-post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:06:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/an-introduction-to-epidemic-modelling/an-introduction-to-epidemic-modelling-post/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how to model an epidemic?
This post is currently a place holder, but will contain the following:
What is epidemic data? How do we model epidemic data? What is the process for getting insights from epidemic data? What methods are used to make inference on those models? What can be done with that inference? This post will be a general overview of the process, and will link to other posts which go deeper into each topic.</description></item><item><title>How to Model Epidemics</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/slides/pydata-oct22/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:06:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/slides/pydata-oct22/</guid><description>Here is a link to the slides of my talk titled: How to Model the Spread of Epidemics
This talk was delivered at the PyData Lancaster October 2022 Meetup.</description></item><item><title>Approximate Bayesian Computation for Epidemics</title><link>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/projects/masters/abcforepi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 13:06:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://BenjamenSimon.github.io/posts/projects/masters/abcforepi/</guid><description>Approximate Bayesian Computation (ABC) is a likelihood-free (sometimes called simulation) method of inference. In this project I present a series of ABC methods which can be used to make approximate inference for epidemic models, and demonstrate their effectiveness on a series of simple case study outbreak datasets. Following this, I apply a selection of the methods to a complex spatio-temporal outbreak dataset for Sugarcane Yellow Leaf Virus. Finally, I discuss some questions that have arisen throughout the project on the use of ABC, and give my judgement on its position as an alternative to MCMC for making inference on epidemic models.</description></item></channel></rss>